我们之前讨论了不同的数据类型，特别是这个uint8或无符号整数
We talked before about different data types in particular this uint8 or unsigned integer
八位数量。让我们稍微看一下数值，我会去
eight bit quantity. Let’s just have a little bit of a look at numeric values and I am going
在这里做一个非常简单的例子。我将创建一个名为A的变量
to do a really trivial example here. I am going to create a variable called A which
等于100，变量名为B，等于200.你可以做一些非常简单的事
is equal to 100, variable called B which is equal to 200. You can do some really simple
算术，你可以弄清楚答案将是什么。
arithmetic and you can work out what the answers are going to be.
A加B为300.减B为-100。除以B等于0.5，完全如我们所愿
A plus B is 300. A minus B is -100. A divided by B is equal to 0.5, all exactly as we would
期望。MATLAB中的这些数字量是双精度数。
expect. These numeric quantities within MATLAB are double precision numbers.
让我们从工作区中删除这些变量。他们都走了，我要创造
Let’s remove these variables from the workspace. They are all gone, and I am going to create
变量现在是uint8类型。所以这个变量A;我们可以看到它是uint8类型和
variables now of uint8 type. So this variable A; we can see it is of the uint8 type and
就像以前一样，它的值为100，但类型不同。我们创建变量
it has got a value of 100 just like before, but the type is different. We create the variable
B，它的值为200，它是uint8类型。所以现在让我们做一些算术。
B, it has got a value of 200 and it is of the uint8 type. So now let’s do some arithmetic.
让我们一起添加A和B.它的值为255。
Lets add A and B together. It has got a value of 255.
减去它们，我们看到值为0.现在让我们进行划分。所以这些答案
Subtract them and we see that the value is 0. Now let’s do a division. So these answers
有点令人惊讶，其原因是无符号整数八
are a little bit surprising and the reason for this is that the unsigned integer eight
位数的动态范围非常有限。
bit numbers have got a very limited dynamic range.
因此，我们在屏幕上看到的结果非常有意义。我添加了两个数字
So the results that we see here on our screen make perfect sense. I add the two numbers
虽然结果应该是300，但它可以达到最大可能值
together and although the results should be 300, the maximum possible value that it can
将uint8类型设为255，这就是MATLAB设置的类型。
have as a uint8 type is 255 and that is what MATLAB has set it to.
同样，它可以拥有的最小可能值是0，所以尽管结果正确
Similarly, the smallest possible value it can have is 0, so although the correct result
是-100，MATLAB将答案设置为0.我们称之为剪裁。结果如此
was -100, MATLAB has set the answer to 0. Well we call it clipping. So the results have
被剪掉了。他们不能低于0，他们不能超过255。
been clipped. They can not go below 0 and they cannot go above 255.
除法结果也有点令人惊讶。这里发生的是A除以
The division result is also a little bit surprising. What has happened here is that A divided by
B，结果为0.5，MATLAB将其舍入到值1.在许多编程中
B, the result is 0.5 and MATLAB has rounded that up to the value of 1. In many programming
语言，如果我将一个小整数除以一个更大的整数，结果将为0.MATLAB
languages, if I divide a small integer by a larger integer the result will be 0. MATLAB
已完成舍入操作，值为1。
has done a rounding operation and given a value of 1.
就实际的计算机硬件而言，uint8类型存储在单个字节中
In terms of the actual computer hardware, the uint8 type is stored in a single byte
计算机的内存。最小的值是所有8位都有一个值
of the computer’s memory. The smallest value is when all of the eight bits have got a value
0，相当于十进制值0.最大值是所有位
of 0, equivalent to a decimal value of 0. And the largest value is when all of the bits
得到的值为1，相当于255的十进制值。
have got a value of 1, which is the equivalent to the decimal value of 255.
对于任意n位整数，最大值为2n^-1。MATLAB支持许多
For an arbitrary n bit integer, the maximum value is 2n^-1. MATLAB supports a number of
其他无符号整数类型;它支持有16位的uint16和uint32
additional unsigned integer types; it supports uint16 which has got 16 bits, and uint32 which
有32位，这些能够表示具有更大的最大值的数字。
has got 32 bits, and these are able to represent numbers with much larger maximum values.
现在我们已经在之前和前面讨论过的图像中显示了这个图像
Now we have displayed this image before and as previously discussed, the pixels in this
image是无符号整数的类型。点击左右，这里我们有整数值
image are of a type unsigned integer. Click around and here we have the integer values
像素。最亮的一个是255;最小的一个将是0。
of the pixels. The brightest one will be 255; the smallest one will be 0.
现在有另一种方法可以表示图像中的像素，我将创建
Now there is another way that we can represent the pixels in an image and I am going to create
一个新的变量，我将它称为imd，imagedouble。我们要做什么
a new variable, I am going to call it imd, image double. And what we are going to do
再次读取图像，但这次是另一个变量。我们将通过
is read the image again, but into a different variable this time. We are going to pass the
选项double，这将做的是将所有像素转换为双精度数，
option double, and what this will do is convert all of the pixels into double precision numbers,
而不是无符号整数。现在让我们显示这个新图像，我会
instead of unsigned integer numbers. Now let’s display this new image and I will
创造一个新的人物。我将在这个新图中显示我的新图像。现在我们看到了
create a new figure. And I will display my new image in this new figure. Now we see it
看起来和另一个看起来完全一样，但如果我在这里点击像素值
looks exactly the same as the other one, but if I click around on the pixel values here
我们现在会看到它们是浮点数。在这个约定中，0表示
we will see that they are floating point numbers now. And in this convention, 0 represents
黑色和1代表白色。所以这是一个相当明亮的数字;在这黑暗中
black and 1 represents white. So this is a reasonably bright number; in the dark of this
门方式，像素值仅为0.03。所以这是另一种表达方式
door way, the pixel values are only 0.03. So this is another way of representing an
图像，每个像素，该矩阵中的每个元素都是双精度数。所以我们有一个
image, each pixel, each element in this matrix is a double precision number. So we have a
这种图像表示中的每个像素值都具有很高的精度。缺点
lot of precision with each of the pixel values in this representation of the image. The disadvantage
是这样的图像需要更多，更多，更多的记忆。
is that such an image requires much, much, more memory.
双精度数占据八个字节的存储空间;uint8只占用
The double precision numbers occupy eight bytes of storage; the uint8 occupies only
一个字节的存储空间，因此右侧的图像占用了8倍多
one byte of storage, so this image on the right-hand side occupies eight times more
记忆比左边的图像。我们可以很容易地看到，使用约
memory than the image on the left. And we can see that quite easily, using the about
功能;告诉我有关变量的信息。我们可以看到它占用1.1兆内存
function; tell me about the variable im. We can see it occupies 1.1 megabytes of memory
在电脑里。让我们看看另一个图像，你可以看到它占据了
in the computer. Let’s have a look at the other image and you can see that it occupies
8.7兆字节。但有时候有优势
8.7 megabytes. But sometimes there are advantages in having
由双精度数表示的像素。
the pixels represented by double precision numbers.
就实际的计算机硬件而言，组织了双精度数
In terms of the actual computer hardware, the double precision number is organised in
像这样的记忆。它占用8个字节的计算机内存或总共64位。
memory like this. It occupies 8 bytes of computer memory or a total of 64 bits.
第一位是符号位，正数为0，a为1
And the first bit is the sign bit and that has got a 0 for a positive number, 1 for a
负数。接下来是11个指数位和52个小数位，我会说
negative number. That is followed by 11 exponent bits and 52 fraction bits and I’ll talk
关于那些片刻。这种特定的布局由IEEE定义
about those in a moment. This particular layout is defined by the IEEE
754标准，所以今天几乎所有计算机上都有浮点数
754 standard, so floating point numbers on almost all computers today are represented
以这种特殊的方式。现在，如果我们用F和表示分数部分
in this particular fashion. Now if we denote the fraction part by F and
指数部分由E表示，实际值表示为Fx2^E.所以E是指数
the exponent part by E, the actual value that is represented is Fx2^E. So the E is the exponent
part和F是我们称之为小数部分-有时也称为尾数。
part and F is what we call the fraction part—sometimes also called the mantissa.
现在，指数的范围是-1022到1021.如果我们从二进制转换
Now, the exponent has got a range of -1022 to 1021. If we do the conversion from binary
在十进制中，我们看到这给了我们这个乘法因子的范围
into decimal, we see that this gives us a range of this multiplication factor which
从10^-308到近10^-307。所以这种数字有了巨大的动力
goes from 10^-308, to almost 10^-307. So this kind of number has got an enormous dynamic
范围。现在指数由11位表示
range. Now the exponent is represented by 11 bits
有2048个可能的不同值。这些值中的四个是保留的，它们是
that has got 2048 possible different values. Four of those values are reserved, they are
特殊的，其中一个用于表示无限数，另一个用于表示
special and one of them is used to represent an infinite number, another is used to represent
负无穷数。一个用于表示所谓的不是数字，所以
a negative infinite number. One is used to represent what is called not a number, so
这是在数字上无效的东西。另一个值用于表示
that is something that is numerically invalid. And another value is used to represent the
精确值为零。分数是有组织的，所以它总是如此
precise value of zero. The fraction is organised so that it is always
因此，分数中最高有效位代表2^-2或1/4。
in the range from 0.5 to 1. So the most significant bit in a fraction represents 2^-2 or 1/4.
最低有效位具有大约10^-16的等效值，因此这意味着这一点
The least significant bit has got an equivalent value of about 10^-16, so that means that this
双精度表示有效地获得了16位有效数字。所以很多数字
double precision representation has got effectively 16 significant digits. So a lot of numeric
精度和非常非常大的动态范围;这是双倍的优势
precision and a very, very, large dynamic range; that is the advantage of this double
计算机内数字的精确浮点表示。
precision floating point representation of numbers within a computer.
现在对精度有一些限制，如果我们考虑这样的数字，0.1，
Now there’s some limits to the precision and if we consider a number like this, 0.1,
这是十进制的十分之一，它没有二进制分数的精确表示。
that is a tenth in decimal, it doesn’t have a precise representation as a binary fraction.
它是二进制的重复部分，因此我们无法准确地表示它。
It is a repeating fraction in binary, so we can’t represent it precisely.
例如，我想查看十进制值90.1。我说
An example of this is, for instance, I want to look at the decimal value 90.1. And I tell
MATLAB以长格式显示，因此显示了很多十进制数字
MATLAB to display this in its long format, so that is showing a lot of decimal digits
而我们看到的是90.1实际上是由90.09999......和最后一位数字在内部表示的
and what we see is that 90.1 is actually represented internally by 90.09999... and the last digit
显示为4.所以在第17位有效数字中是错误的，但正如我们刚才所说的那样
is shown as 4. So it is wrong in the seventeenth significant digit, but as we just talked about
刚才，双精度可以保证你有十六位有效数字，所以
a moment ago, double precision guarantees you around sixteen significant figures, so
这是可以预料的。所以，回顾一下这些不同的数值范围
this is to be expected. So, to recap the numeric ranges of these different
我们用于像素的表示。我们可以将像素表示为无符号
representations that we use for pixels. We can represent pixels as either unsigned
8位整数，每个占用一个字节的计算机内存，它们都有
eight bit integers which would occupy a single byte of computer memory each, and they have
数值范围为0和255.或者我们可以将它们表示为双精度浮点数-它们
a numeric range of 0 and 255. Or we can represent them as double precision floating point numbers—they
每个占用八个字节的计算机存储空间。我们通常将像素强度映射到
occupy eight bytes of computer storage each. And we typically map pixel intensities into
范围0到1,0为暗，1为亮。我们使用时也存在一些困难
the range 0 to 1, 0 being dark, 1 being bright. There are also some difficulties when we use
整数运算。其中一个问题是饱和度，所以如果我们算术的结果
integer arithmetic. One of the problems is saturation, so if the result of our arithmetic
操作超出该表示的最大可能值，它被剪切或
operation exceeds the maximum possible value for that representation, it is clipped or
限于表示的最大可能值。
limited to the maximum possible value for the representation.
所以在这种情况下，算术的结果应该是300.但它被剪裁为255，这就是
So in this case, the result of the arithmetic should be 300. But it is clipped to 255, which
是uint8类型的最大可能值。另一个问题是量化，所以如果我们
is the maximum possible value of a uint8 type. Another problem is quantisation, so if we
看看这两个分区-49除以100给出0的结果-它是有效的
look at these two divisions—49 divided by 100 gives a result of 0—it is effectively
向下舍入为0，而50除以100则向上舍入为1。
rounded down to 0, whereas 50 divided by 100 is rounded up to 1.